Guide to Alone Together: Musicians in a Time of Covid
Alone Together: Musicians in a Time of Covid
Oral History of American Music
Alone Together: Musicians in the Time of Covid
2020
OHVIII
Oral History of American Music
42 Computer Files
6.5 gigabytes
General
41 interviews as of September 9, 2021. OHAM is currently conducting new interviews to add to this collection.
Scope and Contents
A series of Zoom interviews with composers and musicians, focusing on their personal and creative lives while isolating during the COVID-19 outbreak.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research. The finding aid includes links to stream most interviews online via Oral History of American Music's (OHAM) AV access system, Aviary. Yale users can login to Aviary using their Yale University ID, to stream these interviews without restriction. Other users are able to request access to interviews directly through Aviary. For access instructions, and to request transcripts of an interview, see OHAM's website. This finding aid also includes links to Table of Contents for some interviews.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by surname of interviewee.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
.wav and .mp4 files
Composers; Covid-19 (Disease) Social aspects
- Aleskie, Mary Lou
  - Aleskie, Mary Lou, 2020 April 15; OHVIII 4 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 123 megabytes; Approximate running time: 17 mins
    Interview Location
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee located in Hanover, New Hampshire and interviewer in Guilford, CT.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    .mp4 file
    Conditions Governing Access
    As a preservation measure, original computer files may not be used. Digital access copies must be provided for use.
    Aleskie, Mary Lou
- Alexander, Kathryn
  - Alexander, Kathryn, 2020 July 23; OHVIII 35 a; Gancz, Michael; 1 Computer File; 150 megabytes; Approximate running time: 30 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee located in Rockville, MD and interviewer in New Haven, CT.
    Alexander, Kathryn, 1955-
- Alexander, Monty
  - Alexander, Monty, 2020 June 16; OHVIII 25 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 247 megabytes; Approximate running time: 37 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee located in New York, NY and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Alexander, Monty
- Bennett, Matt
  - Bennett, Matt, 2020 July 29; OHVIII 39 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 288 megabytes; Approximate running time: 42 mins
    Scope and Contents
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee located in New York, NY and interviewer located in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    .mp4 files
    Bennett, Matt, 1964-
- Berroa, Ignacio
  - Berroa, Ignacio, 2020 June 29; OHVIII 30 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 186 megabytes; Approximate running time:
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee located in Miami, FL and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Berroa, Ignacio
- Bloom, Jane Ira
  - Bloom, Jane Ira, 2020 April 4; OHVIII 6 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 87.1 megabytes; Approximate running time: 18 mins
    Interview Location:
    Interview conducted via video chat. Interviewee located in New York, NY and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Bloom, Jane Ira
- Brecker, Randy
  - Brecker, Randy, 2020 April 29; OHVIII 10 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 123 megabytes; Approximate running time: 25 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat. Interviewee located in Long Island, NY and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Brecker, Randy
- Bresnick, Martin
  - Bresnick, Martin, 2020 April 13; OHVIII 3 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 77.5 megabytes; Approximate running time: 18 mins
    Interview conducted via video chat with interviewee located in New Haven, CT and interviewer in Guilford, CT.
    Bresnick, Martin, 1946-
- Brown, Michael
  - Brown, Michael, 2020 May 18; OHVIII 19 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 39.5 megabytes; Approximate running time: 15 mins
    Brown, Michael, 1987-
- Ellis, T. D.
  - Ellis, T. D., 2020 June 15; OHVIII 23 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 135 megabytes; Approximate running time: 20 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee in West Hartford, CT, and interviewer in Guildford, CT.
    Ellis, T.D.
- Escoffery, Wayne
  - Escoffery, Wayne, 2020 April 29; OHVIII 12 a; Serrambana, Nicholas; 1 Computer File; 987 megabytes; Approximate running time: 14 mins
    Interview conducted via video chat with interviewee located in New York, NY and interviewer located New Haven, CT.
    Escoffery, Wayne
- Hayes, Louis
  - Hayes, Louis, 2020 June 30; OHVIII 32 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 82.5 megabytes; Approximate running time: 15 mins
    Interview created via videochat, with interviewee located in New York, NY and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Hayes, Louis, 1937-
- Jordan, Sheila
  - Jordan, Sheila, 2020 June 30; OHVIII 33 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 175 megabytes; Approximate running time: 33 mins
    Jordan, Sheila, 1928-
- Kaczmarek, Konrad
  - Kaczmarek, Konrad, 2020 June 24; OHVIII 24 a; Gancz, Michael; 1 Computer File; 157 megabytes; Approximate running time: 27 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee located in Hamden, CT and interviewer located in New Haven, CT.
    Kaczmarek, Konrad
- Kapilian, Danny
  - Kapilian, Danny, 2020 June 17; OHVIII 27 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 100 megabytes; Approximate running time: 38 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewer located in Brooklyn, NY and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Kapilian, Danny
- Kendrick, James
  - Kendrick, James, 2020 June 10; OHVIII 22 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 104 megabytes; Approximate running time: 29 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee located in Ridgewood, NJ and interviewer in Guildford, CT.
    Kendrick, James M., 1952-
- Kiley, Shannon
  - Kiley, Shannon, 2020 November 25; OHVIII 41 a; Gancz, Michael; 1 Computer File; 267 megabytes; Approximate running time: 24 minutes
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in New Haven, CT and interviewer in Rockville, MD.
    mp4 file
    Kiley, Shannon
- Lake, Oliver
  - Lake, Oliver, 2020 April 30; OHVIII 13 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 76.9 megabytes; Approximate running time: 17 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee and interviewer both in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Lake, Oliver, 1942-
- Lankenau, Steven
  - Lankenau, Steven, 2020 June 17; OHVIII 26 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 138 megabytes; Approximate running time: 35 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee located in Brooklyn, NY and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Lankenau, Steven
- Lavin, Christine
  - Lavin, Christine, 2020 June 29; OHVIII 31 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 216 megabytes; Approximate running time: 27 mins
    Lavin, Christine
- Lipetz, Shlomo
  - Lipetz, Shlomo, 2020 July 31; OHVIII 40 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 248 megabytes; Approximate running time: 32 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Brooklyn, NY and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Lipetz, Schlomo
- Lockwood, Annea
  - Lockwood, Annea, 2020 April 8; OHVIII 1 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 116 megabytes; Approximate running time: 14 mins
    Interview conducted vie videochat. Interviewee located in Crompond, NY and interviewer in Guildford, CT.
    Lockwood, Annea, 1939-
- Martin, Steve
  - Martin, Steve, 2020 July 19; OHVIII 34 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 417 megabytes; Approximate running time: 30 mins
    Interview location
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee located in Bedford, NY and interviewer located in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Martin, Steve (Booking Agent)
- McLaughlin, John
  - McLaughlin, John, 2020 April 30; OHVIII 14 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 157 megabytes; Approximate running time: 35 mins
    Inverview conducted via videochat. Interviewee located in Monaco and interviewer located in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    McLaughlin, John, 1942-
- Oppens, Ursula
  - Oppens, Ursula, 2020 April 27; OHVIII 8 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 104 megabytes; Approximate running time: 19 mins.
    Interview conducted via videochat. Interviewee located in New York, NY, and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Oppens, Ursula, 1944-
- Osterlund, Markus
  - Osterlund, Markus, 2020 March 27; OHVIII 9 a; Martinez, Olivia; 1 Computer File; 1.22 gigabytes; Approximate running time: 64 mins.
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee in Washington, D.C. and interviewer in Mishawaka, IN.
    Osterlund, Markus
- Reich, Steve
  - Reich, Steve, 2020 April 28; OHVIII 11 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 49.2 megabytes; Approximate running time: 24 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat. Interviewee located in Los Angeles, CA and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Reich, Steve, 1936-
- Rollins, Sonny
  - Rollins, Sonny, 2020 June 1; OHVIII 21 a; Bendian, Gregg; 2 Computer Files; 1.6 gigabytes
    Interview conducted via phone, with interviewee in Woodstock, NY and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Approximate running time: 66 mins.
    .wav file
    Rollins, Sonny
- Rosenboom, David
  - Rosenboom, David, 2020 July 30; OHVIII 36 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 483 megabytes; Approximate running time: 45 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee located in Valencia, CA and interviewer in Guilford, CT.
    Rosenboom, David
- Sellars, Peter
  - Sellars, Peter, 2020 May 8; OHVIII 17 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 219 megabytes; Approximate running time: 42 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee in Los Angeles, CA and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Sellars, Peter
- Sheng, Bright
  - Sheng, Bright, 2020 April 27; OHVIII 7 a; Bendian, Gregg; Sheng, Bright, 1955-; 1 Computer File; 173 megabytes; Approximate running time: 23 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee in Ann Arbor, MI and interviewer in Fairl Lawn, NY.
- Shepard, Chris
  - Shepard, Chris, 2020 May 4; OHVIII 16 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 139 megabytes; Approximate running time: 26 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat. Interviewee located in Clinton, CT and interviewer in Guilford, CT.
    Shepard, Chris
- Sierra, Roberto
  - Sierra, Roberto, 2020 April 30; OHVIII 15 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 93.4 megabytes; Approximate running time: 22 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat. Interviewee located in Camillus, NY and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Sierra, Roberto
- Stasium, Ed
  - Stasium, Ed, 2020 June 19; OHVIII 28 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 268 megabytes; Approximate running time: 32 mins
    Interview Locations
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee located in Poway, CA and interviewer located in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Stasium, Ed
- Swallow, Steve
  - Swallow, Steve, 2020 June 22; OHVIII 29 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 663 megabytes; Approximate running time: 44 mins
    Interview conducted via phone call, with interviewee located in Willow, NY and interviewer located in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Swallow, Steve
- Taber, Randy
  - Taber, Randy, 2020 July 23; OHVIII 38 a; Bendian, Gregg; 1 Computer File; 191 megabytes; Approximate running time: 30 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat, with interviewee in Maywood, NJ and interviewer in Fair Lawn, NJ.
    Taber, Randy
- Valverde, Hugo
  - Valverde, Hugo, 2020 April 19; OHVIII 5 a; Martinez, Olivia; 1 Computer File; 527 megabytes; Approximate running time: 87 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat. Interviewee located in Barva, Costa Rica and interviewer in Mishawaka, IN.
    Valverde, Hugo
- Vees, Jack
  - Vees, Jack, 2020 May 11; OHVIII 18 a; Wolf, Samantha; 1 Computer File; 214 megabytes; Approximate running time: 25 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee in Guilford, CT and interviewer in New Haven, CT.
    Vees, Jack (1955-)
- Verdery, Benjamin
  - Verdery, Benjamin, 2020 April 11; OHVIII 2 a; Van Cleve, Libby; 1 Computer File; 129 megabytes; Approximate running time: 22 mins
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee located in New York, NY and interviewer located in Guilford, CT.
    Verdery, Benjamin
- Wightman, Ross
  - Wightman, Ross, 2020 August 6; OHVIII 37 a; Serrambana, Nicholas; 1 Computer File; 82.9 megabytes; Approximate running time: 18 mins.
    Interview conducted via videnchat with interviewee in Maplewood, NJ and interviewer in New Haven, CT.
    Wightman, Ross
- Younan, Elizabeth
  - Younan, Elizabeth, 2020 May 8; OHVIII 20 a; Wolf, Samantha; 1 Computer File; 192 megabytes; Approximate running time: 28 mins.
    Interview conducted via videochat with interviewee in Sydney, Australia, and interviewer in New Haven, CT.
    Younan, Elizabeth